How far would you go to save the family business?
Kinky Boots is a comedy, drama, music film directed by Julian Jarrold.
Charles Price may have grown up with his father in the family shoe business in Northampton,
central England, but he never thought that he would take his father's place.
Charles has a chance encounter with the flamboyant drag queen
cabaret singer Lola and everything changes.
Charlie Price, played by Joel Edgerton.
Lola/Simon, played by Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Lauren, played by Sarah-Jane Potts.
Don, played by Nick Frost.
Mel, played by Linda Bassett.
Nicola, played by Jemima Rooper.
Kinky Boots is a 2005 British comedy-drama film directed by Julian
Jarrold and written by Geoff Deane and Tim Firth.
The film, based on true events, tells of struggling shoe factory owner Charlie, who forms
an unlikely partnership with Lola, a drag queen, to save the business.
Charlie develops a plan to produce custom footwear for drag queens, rather than the men's
dress shoes that his firm is known for, alienating many in the process.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and later developed a cult
following and inspired the 2013 stage musical of the same name.
The film explores themes of factory worker, career,
factory, small town, transvestism.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.